In the previous notebook,
在上一个 notebook 中
you saw a way of making recommendations using collaborative filtering.
我们演示了如何通过协同过滤推荐电影
In this notebook, we're going to take a look at a little bit of
在此 notebook 中 我们将学习另一种
a different way to make recommendations based on the actual content.
基于实际内容的推荐方法
The way that we'll do that with the dataset we're working with in this lesson is by
在这节课 我们将查看
looking at the content associated with the movies
与 movies 数据集相关的内容
and then trying to find movies that have similar content.
然后尝试查找内容相似的电影
Specific to our dataset,
对于 movies 数据集来说
we can look at a header of the movies,
我们来看看表格的标题部分
and the idea is that we might use the year that the movie was created or
我们可以查看电影制作年份
the genre associated with the movie to better
或电影类型
understand what movies might be most similar to it.
了解与该电影最相似的电影
You also could do something with natural language processing to try to
你还可以使用自然语言处理方法
find movies that are similar in terms of the title
通过片名查找相似的电影
or if you had like the actual transcript of the movie,
如果有电影剧本的话
you could try to find movies that were similar based on having similar transcripts.
还可以根据相似的剧本查找相似的电影
Those are maybe more advanced than the techniques we'll look at this lesson,
这些技巧比在这节课介绍的更加先进
specifically because we don't actually have a lot of that information available to us.
因为我们没有掌握这么多的信息
We'll do our best with sort of looking at these last dummy columns that
所以我们将查看我们创建的
we created to try to figure out
最后几个虚拟列
how movies are related to one another based on the content.
尽量根据这些内容判断电影之间的关系
In this first part here,
在第一部分
we're going to take a look at which users didn't
我们将查看在使用协同过滤时
actually get enough recommendations based on collaborative filtering,
哪些用户没有获得足够多的推荐电影
and not enough in our case will be anyone who didn't have more than nine,
也就是推荐电影不超过 9 部
who didn't receive 10 or more recommendations using collaborative filtering.
没有使用协同过滤向他们推荐 10 部及以上的电影
Up here, when we read stuff in,
我们在这里读取了数据
you can see we have this all_recs thing,
这里有个 all_recs
which is essentially a dictionary where the key is a user and
它是一个字典 键是用户
the value is a list of recommendations for that user.
值是向该用户推荐的电影列表
So, the key is the user ID and the value
所以键是用户 ID
In order to figure out the users who have all of the recs,
为了查看具有足够多推荐电影的用户
essentially we want to loop through this all_recs dictionary.
我们将遍历这个 all_recs 字典
Basically, if the length of the movies array is greater than nine,
如果 movies 数组的长度大于 9
we'll append to that user.
我们将附加该用户
This is basically saying if they have
这部分代码的作用是
10 or more movies that have been recommended to them,
如果向此用户推荐了 10 部及以上的电影
then they have all of their recs.
那么返回 all_recs
Otherwise, we'll say that they still need recommendations and these are essentially
否则这些用户依然需要推荐电影
the users that we want to focus on for the content-based recommendations.
这些用户是基于内容的推荐方式需要侧重的用户
So, it looks like that worked out okay.
代码能正常运行了
It looks like we had 31,000 users
结果显示协同过滤方法依然没有向
who didn't get 10 or more ratings based on collaborative filtering.
31,000 位用户推荐 10 部及以上的电影